

Mikael Vatau Software Developer

- Swedish
- Unmarried

Skills

| Software development | 13l+ Year |
|----------------------|-----------|
| Customer service | 7+ Years |
| Embedded systems | 8+ yrs. |
| Linux | 15+ yrs. |
| Web development | 2+ yrs. |
| C / C++ | 10+ yrs. |
| РНР | 2+ yrs. |
| Python | 2+ yrs. |
| Swedish | L1 |
| English | C1 |
| | |

Biography

Eight years experience developing mobile phone platform and almost 13 year experience in embedded system development both hardware and software. Worked with audio, GPS, touchscreen, Bluetooth, WLAN and motor control in large and small scaled project. Seven years experience in customer care.

Work experience

Technical Support

Sep 2017 - Oct 2023

Accenture

Technical support for Google Adwords and Analytics

Customer Support

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017

CGI Portugal

Supporting both interal and customer in IT

Customer Support

Sep 2015 - Aug 2019

Teleperformance

Supporting Swedish customers (Photobox, Boxer)

Software Consultant

Mar 2005 - Apr 2019

Netville AB

I was involved in software configuration, low-level audio development, GPS, touch screen, WLAN, Bluetooth, on-site technical support, and application development during my 8-year tenure at Netville:

- Camera Web Interface Development (5 months) at Axis Communications for their security cameras.
- Platform-Based Applications Development (1 year) at Sony Ericsson: Collaborated on Android applications, such as the calendar, and clock in a small team of 2 that expanded to eight members and 10 applications.
- Low-Level Audio Development (2 years) at ST-Ericsson: Involved development for Low Power audio, Wideband Bluetooth, and ALSA, including providing on-site support in Asia and Sweden.
- Accessibility App Development (3 months) for Netville Customer: Developed an Android application aiding visually impaired individuals.
- Test Software Development (1 year) at Sony Ericsson Mobile Communications AB: to be run on phone to test the GPS signal-to-noise redusing the test time from 30 to 4 seconds.
- Configuration Management and Development (4 years) at Ericsson AB: Initially serving as Configuration Manager, later transitioning into a developer role within the Open Platform Architecture department in addition to configuringand supporting PC-lint tool.

Interests

- Piano
- Chess
- Travel

Contact

- Rua Heliodoro 22a 1170-177 Lisbon
- □ +351 926 888 037
- sleepbrunch@gmail.com
- github.com/secratry

Research Engineer

Robotics Lunds, University

Worked almost 5 years in multiple hardware and software projects, Maintaining of the departments computer and with development of their website.

- Network administration of the departments computers. (IRIX, Linux, and Windows)
- Assisted in developing the departments new website (news page and document repository).
- Assisted in developing the departments new website (news page and document repository).
- Implement, verify and troubleshot controller cards based on 32bit Freescale CPU for DC and Step motor control.
- Implement, verify and troubleshot controller cards based on 32bit Freescale CPU for DC and Step motor control.
- Hardware and software for controllers to be used in on a robotics arm on attached to a wheelchair (they used the CAN protocoll for communication).
- Worked with an EU project, designing and implementing the controllers and software to be used in bottle openers for physically disabled people.

Education

- 2009, SEMC AB (EMEA) Linux for Embedded Systems Advanced
- 2008, Ericsson AB Linux for Embedded Systems
- 2006, Ericsson AB GPRS Security
- 2003, Malmo University Practical English in Cross-cultural Communications
- 2000, SGI IRIX System Administration
- 1997 2000, Lunds Institute of Technology B.Sc.E. Electro Engineer

Publications

- Author, G. & Author, P. & Author G. (2020). "This is the title of the publication".
 In: Proceedings of the 28th Conference on Lipsum (LIPSUM), Lipsum, June 12-17, 2020.
- Author, G. & Author, P. & Author G. (2020). "This is the title of the publication".
 In: Proceedings of the 28th Conference on Lipsum (LIPSUM), Lipsum, June 12-17, 2020.
- Author, G. & Author, P. & Author G. (2020). "This is the title of the publication".
 In: Proceedings of the 28th Conference on Lipsum (LIPSUM), Lipsum, June 12-17, 2020.